<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog Title</title>
    <link>http://sample.com</link>
    <pubDate>2013-02-10 02:00:05 -0700</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>Fat</title>
      <link>http://sample.com/articles/fat.html</link>
      <pubDate>2013-02-10</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Negative Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little while ago we released this comic in which we used the word fat
and we had one complaint that it was offensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sphotos-b.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ash4/299542_493943143989770_1084414739_n.png" alt="Big &amp;amp; Tall"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;The Defense Takes the Stand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t disagree that a person would feel offended.
People are offended by lots of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I want to put forth a case as to why it was appropriate
(and perhaps necessary) to use the word fat in all of its glory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(read through to the end before getting in a huff,
there&amp;#39;s some legitimate reasoning here)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;America has a lot of overweight people
(overweight is so much longer of a word than fat).
Although some people claim that obesity
(a word which implies not just an image issue, but also a medical condition)
is heriditary and yada yada.
I&amp;#39;ll argue &lt;em&gt;FALSE&lt;/em&gt;.
False in the sense that weight gain or loss is more strongly
associated with calorie intake than any other factor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some&lt;/em&gt; people are &lt;strong&gt;big-boned&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;em&gt;Some&lt;/em&gt; people have &lt;strong&gt;slower metabolisms&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;em&gt;All&lt;/em&gt; people gain weight if their calorie intake is higher than what they burn.
Obesity isn&amp;#39;t a &lt;em&gt;world problem&lt;/em&gt; like a viral infection or birth defect.
It&amp;#39;s a &lt;em&gt;first-world problem&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My point is that you can take reasonable measures to adjust your weight
to be what you desire.
Two friends of mine have lost 50+ pounds in the past year.
The didn&amp;#39;t like their image and they changed it.
Hurrah for my friends!
:-D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_2"&gt;A Tangent&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shorter people can also wear high heels, boots - or even have
surgery to become taller.
Tall people can&amp;#39;t wear something to become shorter
(and I&amp;#39;ve never heard of surgeries to make one shorter either).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excessive shortness is considered a handicap and in order to make things
more &lt;em&gt;accessible&lt;/em&gt; to the handicapped (and children) many things are built
&lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; too close to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet excessive height isn&amp;#39;t considered a handicap and we&amp;#39;re supposed to just
deal with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What about our accessibility?&lt;/strong&gt; Are we lesser people because we&amp;#39;re tall?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Think of the Children!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, I can agree with that.
100% of people go through a short phase.
Only about 10% of people go through a tall &lt;del&gt;phase&lt;/del&gt;.
That&amp;#39;s fair. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_3"&gt;Back on track&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It really doesn&amp;#39;t make sense as to why words like &lt;em&gt;fat&lt;/em&gt; should be taboo.
There are many other terms that apply to people who are making lifestyle
choices that negatively affect their image which are not considered taboo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example, it&amp;#39;s not considered culturally insensitive to inspecifically
&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/MethProject"&gt;address a group of drug addicts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But whatever, the truth is that &lt;em&gt;fat&lt;/em&gt; is often considered an offensive word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_4"&gt;We&amp;#39;ve got hurt feelings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having established that &lt;em&gt;fat&lt;/em&gt; is often taboo,
now it&amp;#39;s time to explain why we
(the tall community)
&lt;a href="http://youtu.be/9zI3_pnUU3k"&gt;are crying tears of a rapper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tall people complain about not being able to find clothes that fit.
Non-tall people invariably chip in with their advice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you tried big and tall?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the phrase &amp;quot;Big &amp;amp; Tall&amp;quot; is a lie -
whether referring to the official JC Penney trademark or any of the
assortment of various stores with a similar claim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These stores use &lt;em&gt;Tall&lt;/em&gt; as part of their euphemism to attract &lt;em&gt;big&lt;/em&gt; people
without offending them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s basic marketing psychology.
The idea is that the subconscious thought and feeling of a potential customer
will go something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I go to the Big store then I&amp;#39;m fat, which is &lt;em&gt;taboo&lt;/em&gt;.
But if I go to the Big and Tall
store then maybe I&amp;#39;m Big, or maybe I&amp;#39;m Tall  -
and Tall is &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; so I can
&lt;em&gt;brag&lt;/em&gt; that I shop at a big &lt;em&gt;and tall&lt;/em&gt; store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reality big and tall stores don&amp;#39;t have lengths that are any longer than
would be expected in accordance with normal size progression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, we&amp;#39;re born this way.
It&amp;#39;s not something we can change by changing our lifestyle.
It&amp;#39;s not that we have anything against the fat,
it&amp;#39;s that we don&amp;#39;t like that this double-euphemism &lt;strong&gt;comes at the &lt;em&gt;our&lt;/em&gt; expense&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An &lt;em&gt;extra large&lt;/em&gt; is maybe 2 inches longer than a &lt;em&gt;small&lt;/em&gt;.
For many brands and styles, an &lt;em&gt;LT&lt;/em&gt; and an &lt;em&gt;XXXL&lt;/em&gt; (pronounced triple-X L)
are exactly the same size - they&amp;#39;re simply relabeled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We (speaking for many a tall person) are a little bitter about that.
There&amp;#39;s some hurt feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve all had the experience of thinking we&amp;#39;ve found something that will fit well,
only to find out that &lt;a href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=the%20cake%20is%20a%20lie"&gt;the cake is a lie&lt;/a&gt;.
That breeds some resentment - again not towards the fat,
more towards the companies that use us to their advantage without giving us
the promise product in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(That said, it&amp;#39;s worth noting that all though a MT from the regular section
&lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; be legitimately Medium Tall -
but it&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; rare to find one -
whereas an MT from a big and tall section is almost always a XXL or XXXL relabeled)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s the underlying psyschology of why we (Men&amp;#39;s Medium Tall)
chose to use the word &lt;em&gt;fat&lt;/em&gt;.
If we just said &lt;em&gt;big&lt;/em&gt;,
then we would fit into the stereotype of protecting group A at the expense of group B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, we&amp;#39;re group Tall and at this stage in the game we need the Tall to know
that we&amp;#39;re on &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; side.
Not the side of the &lt;a href="http://www.cdc.gov/nchs/fastats/overwt.htm"&gt;69.2%&lt;/a&gt;.
Not the politically correct side.
Not the side of the &lt;a href="http://answers.google.com/answers/threadview/id/325064.html"&gt;95%&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On the side of the top 10%.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. In that 10% we&amp;#39;re al actually includes people who have long torsos&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
